COSTA DAVID-ANTON

Video Game Programmer

@ costa.anton@hotmail.com
 https://antoncosta.github.io/

INTRODUCTION

Hello.

I'm Costa, a video game programmer from Romania, experienced with mobile, desktop and web development. I am an open-minded, hard-working individual who consistently strives to attain new knowledge and new experiences. Curiosity has always pushed me forward to try new things and I, without fail, have the perseverance to finish what I start. I consider myself to be a fast learner, or, at the very least, persevering enough to learn as quickly as possible. I have studied in multiple countries and I have quickly adapted to all of the new environments I was placed into.

EXPERIENCE

VR Developer

Luminess Romania

MOCt 2023 - Present

♥ Cluj-Napoca, Cluj, Romania

• I am currently employed as a Unity VR Developer. In a team with 5 other programmers and 5 artists, we develop serious games to be used as educational/training material for different working environments. Examples include a hydrogen power plant, a crèche, and a wind power plant. We are coordinated by our leaders in the French branch of Luminess and our client is the French Ministry of Education. We are also working in parallel with the Indian team who are handling different scenarios at the same time as us, using the same framework which is developed by both teams.

Gameplay Programmer

Tractor Set GO!

math Dec 2021 - Aug 2023

♥ Cluj-Napoca, Cluj, Romania

• During my time at the company I have worked on multiple projects, mostly as a gameplay programmer but for two shorter projects as a solo developer. One project and my first one, was an NFT based top-down shooter. The game is developed in Unity and I was mainly programming gameplay features (combat, abilities, weapons) and occasionally setting up sounds, animations and effects. I have worked on an educational web-based RPG that wants to teach children about cybersecurity and how to stay safe in an online environment. I have also developed 2 small VR applications used for presentation purposes, one for city planning and one for car airbags.

EXPERIENCE

Game Developer for Card Game Freelance

m Oct 2020 - May 2022

• This project started as freelance work but at the moment it's on standby. I didn't give its name but I can describe a bit of how it behaves at the moment. It is a browserbased collectible card game, meant to be played online, with RPG elements and heavy emphasis on your hero card, the cards in your deck meant to support them. The map is randomly generated, each hex providing different benefits and affecting each class differently. The game is made in Unity using C# and I have used Mirror Networking for the multiplayer element. There are also a couple of shaders made by me using HLSL. The server was deployed on AWS and the client as well. There is a matchmaking system in place and multiple games of two players can be held at the same time.

Solitaire Expert

Freelance

max Dec 2019 - May 2020

 The game is a variant of the classic solitaire game, made in Unity using C# and a bit of HLSL. I added a lot of functionality and visuals to a game that was in a basic state and I deployed it on the Google Play Store and Apple App Store. The game was made as a commission while I was studying in Groningen, Netherlands.

Full Stack Developer ARRK Research & Development

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

 In my probation period I had small introductory Python and Angular projects, some for external clients, some for internal use. After that I had been assigned to ongoing full stack BMW projects. I had been working in a team with multiple people and we were using Angular, nestJS and deployment on AWS.

EXPERIENCE

European Economic Area(EEA) Placement Grant University of Iceland

Reykjavík, Iceland

 A two-month mobility in Iceland to work at the university on a research project. I developed a Virtual Reality application in the Unity game engine to help people that suffer from Acrophobia (fear of heights).

Full time Programmer/Localisation Engineer Pragmatic Play

♀ Bucharest, Romania

 A Unity game engine developer for slot games. My task was to create Unity editor extensions, or to continue existing extensions, to help streamline the game production. I was also part of the localisations team and we were responsible for the maintenance of the application.

Intern

Property Shark

mar 2018 - Sep 2018

 A six-month period of internship. One half of it working with Visual Basic to do User Acceptance Tests. The second half was with C# creating and modifying ASP.NET applications. Both of them related the "PropertyShark - Real Estate Search and Property Information " website

EDUCATION

Master's Degree, Graphics, Multimedia and Virtual Reality

University Politehnica of Bucharest

2018 - 2020

♀ Bucharest, Romania

The Master focused on Computer Graphics mostly, OpenGL, C++ and video game engines, video game design and development, as well as a bit of marketing advice. Along with game engine, there was also an emphasis on Virtual Reality, as most university projects related to virtual reality were done by the computer graphics department.

Master's Degree, Computer Graphics

University of Groningen

2019 - 2020

Part of an ERASMUS+ study exchange. I have continued the master's that I have started in Bucharest on Computer Graphics, Multimedia and Virtual Reality.

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Babes-Bolyai University

2015 - 2018

♥ Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Web development focused, emphasis on OOP, it's principles and mobile applications as well as website development for mobile environments.

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

AGH University of Science and Technology

2017 - 2017

◊ Kraków, Poland

Exchange student for one semester with ERASMUS+. I mainly did courses in the field of Computer Science which were equivalent with what I would have done back home, one exception being a Polish Language course which was for exchange students.

High School, Mathematics and Informatics

National College "Gheorghe Sincai"

2011 - 2015

Paia Mare, Romania

SKILLS

Unity
C#
Mirror Networking
AWS
AR&VR
Unreal
C, C++
Java
Angular
Python
JavaScript
TypeScript

INTERESTS

Technical

- Video Game Programming and Design
- Shaders & Computer Graphics
- Front-end web development
- Back-end web development

Hobbies

- Playing video games.
- Writing fantasy stories.
- Travelling.
- Listening to audio books.
- Juggling and Magic.

LANGUAGES

English
Romanian
French
Polish
Japanese

REFERENCES

Prof. Dr. Ing. Alin Moldoveanu @ alin.moldoveanu@cs.pub.ro

Dr. Jiří Kosinka @ j.kosinka@rug.nl

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Fast learner Curious
Imaginative Adaptable

Game Engines

Video Game Design & Development

Mobile Applications

Web Development